Dustin Royer

Wimauma, FL

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Dustin-Royer/fc2769caa26ea7e9

Professional Summary

BACKGROUND SUMMARY: IT Director / Sr Systems Architect / Sr Systems Engineer / Business Owner

US Air Force veteran with active TOP SECRET Security Clearance, 40% disability rating, and over 26 years of experience in IT Management, System Engineering and Architecture, Cloud Integration, Cyber Security, Project

Management, Web Design, Database Administration, and Audio/Visual.

Looking for Work Opportunities as: VP of IT, IT Director, or Senior Systems Architect/Engineer

Related areas of LEADERSHIP/MANAGEMENT BUSINESS EXPERIENCE:

I have effectively managed personnel (700+), resources (100,000 plus nodes), budgets, training, and project timelines throughout my career. I understand that to be successful you must work smarter and not necessarily harder. I understand that people are the biggest asset to any organization and maintain a leadership versus management mentality that promotes a sense of personal ownership and accountability. I believe that good mentoring and communication, along with a clear understanding of the big picture enable you to set realistic and attainable goals that enable personnel to effectively contribute to the success of the organization and succeed in their own personal or professional growth and development.

Work Experience

Director of Information Technology

Microsoft-Tampa, FL April 2013 to Present

Managed the Information Technology department across multiple operating facilities. Provided direct Work directly with executive management and business units to properly align business functions to technology in order to maintain the company's competitive posture in the market place. Act as the technical point of contact to iGov customers. Provide technical expertise to support Sales and Business Development.

High-Level Project Highlights: Completely redesigned the IT Infrastructure (Cisco/VMWare/NetAPP) to eliminate single points or failure; Multiple Client Hardware upgrades; Multiple email migrations (2007-2013-

Microsoft 365 Commercial, Microsoft 365 Government Cloud GCC-HIGH); Multiple SharePoint migrations (2007-2010-2013); Datacenter migration and deployment of COOP/DR Site; Development of new iGov public

Website; Multiple Audio/Visual conference room Install/Upgrades;

Cloud Integration: Microsoft 365 commercial to Microsoft GCC-HIGH Migration, On-Premise Exchange/Lync to Office 365 cloud, On-Premise helpdesk system migrated to cloud (Track IT to Manage Engine), On-

Premise malware to cloud; Windows 10 Client Upgrade

Portfolio of support: CISCO, NETAPP, VMWARE, HP, IBM, DELL, Microsoft Server, Active Directory, Exchange/LYNC, SharePoint, SQL server, TrendMicro, Windows Deployment Services, PDQ, Manage Engine, Navision, COGNOS, DELTEK Suite, Apple/Mac

Technical Director

South Bay, FL July 2011 to October 2013 Coordinate all aspect of the congregational worship service, to include multimedia presentation, Front of House sound, Lighting, Video recording, graphics, and volunteer scheduling. Lead and coordinate set design changes. Led several sequential projects to upgrade the lighting infrastructure, improve building acoustics, and improve Video

Recording capabilities.

Enterprise Exchange Architect SAIC-Macdill AFB, FL January 2012 to April 2013

Lead Architect responsible for all Enterprise messaging initiatives within the US CENTRAL COMMAND Enterprise.

Custom developed a fully automated set of Configuration and Reporting Tools that dynamically collects all relevant

Exchange and Active Directory configuration settings and provides report metrics through a web based interface that significantly enhanced the organizations ability to assess changes from the baseline and identify performance bottlenecks. Responsibilities include: Technical oversight for all planning, design, testing, and documentation related to the exchange enterprise. Serve as the Principal escalation point for all tier 3 related incidents and technical oversight for all messaging related project initiatives.

USCENTCOM Contractor (US Central Command)-Macdill AFB, FL July 2010 to April 2013

Held 2 different subsequent contractor positions with USCENTCOM due to contract switch over mid employment.

Sr Systems Engineering / Project Manager

InScope International-Macdill AFB, FL July 2010 to January 2012

Contracted as the technical lead responsible for all of the operations related projects initiatives in support of the

USCENTCOM enterprise networks. Acted as one of several project managers on the construction of a new headquarters building. Provided both technical and project management oversight for the construction of the new datacenter. Provided oversight and assisted in the development of a migration strategy to: upgrade all core infrastructure services (CISCO, Juniper, F5), implement a tiered EMC storage area network architecture, created a standardize virtualization strategy with VM Ware, upgrade all networks from Active

Directory/Exchange 2003 to Active Directory 2008/Exchange 2010, migration/transition and/or upgrade of all enterprise applications (Blackberry, SharePoint, SCOM, SCCM, Unix/Linux services, etc.) Additional responsibilities include: Deputy Operations Manager and primary escalation engineer for all enterprise tier 3 incidents.

Managing Principal Systems Engineer

Konica Minolta (Danka)-Saint Petersburg, FL May 2008 to March 2010

Provided Management and technical oversight for all enterprise Applications and Network Infrastructure including the direct management of 5 System/Network Engineers and technical oversight over 700 sales field support engineers through the US and Europe. Management of the engineering responsibilities included: Infrastructure

Management (Voice and Data), Active Directory 2003/Exchange2003 (2500+ Users), SharePoint, Disaster Recovery, and Security. Also, worked closely with the business and Marketing departments in developing and maintaining E-Commerce and Corporate web presence. Project List: Implementation of SharePoint 2007, Microsoft

Sr Systems Engineering Consultant

Infinite Computer Solutions (Verizon)-Tampa, FL November 2007 to May 2008 As Verizon FIOS Video Operations Infrastructure Support Engineer. Designed and implemented Microsoft Systems

Center Operations Manager 2007 environment to monitor and report performance metrics for the FIOS Video

Infrastructure (300+ server) across 12 geographically separate Video Hub Offices. Under terms of contract I provide support for all infrastructure (Active Directory, Patch management, Monitoring, Reporting), database, and web applications.

System Center Operations Manager

Microsoft

January 2007 to December 2007

Live Communications Server, WSUS 3.0, McAfee Total

Protection Enterprise. Convergence, Implementation and Migration of 12 separate mixed Konica Minolta legacy networks gained through acquisition into 1 single Forest Active Directory 2008/Exchange 2007 Network.

Sr Systems Engineering Consultant

Sky Bridge Recourses (Pharmerica)-Tampa, FL August 2007 to November 2007

Assisted in design and implementation of datacenter migration to relocate entire datacenter from Tampa FL facility to Kentucky facility to; Including Active Directory, Exchange 2003, SQL Servers, File/Print Server Environment, and web applications.

Senior Network/Systems Engineer

WellCare Inc.-Tampa, FL April 2006 to June 2007

Lead engineer provided technical and project management oversight for all enterprise messaging applications;

Microsoft Exchange 2003 (5000 + users), Blackberry enterprise (500 + users), and Right fax enterprise (2500+ users). Designed, maintained, and implemented fault tolerant clustered Exchange 2003, archive, spam/virus filtering solution: Merged 8 separate 2003 Exchange servers with localized storage and 16 mail stores per server into a 4 node fault tolerant 3 active 1 passive cluster with San connected storage. Implemented Mimosa Near

Point disk archiving solution; significantly reduced existing Exchange storage from over 3TB to under 1TB by archiving to SAN. Implemented Iron Port clustered C300 Spam appliance with end user quarantines to handle the load of over 2 million inbound email messages per week. Designed fault tolerant Right Fax 9.x clustered enterprise network to include: Clustered Application server, Clustered SQL 2000 migrated to SQL 2005 on win 64x, and 3 board servers with Brook Trout T1 cards with 120 channels and 5 dedicated T1 connections.

Senior Systems Administrator

MP TotalCare Inc. /CCS Medical-Tampa, FL March 2005 to April 2006

Design and maintain a Windows 2003 / Exchange 2003 enterprise network in order to bring together nine geographically separated WindowsNT networks, acquired through acquisition of several new companies.

Responsible for overall design and deployment of Wide Area Network, Active Directory, DNS, OU structure, Sites hierarchy, Group Policies, IP sub netting, Exchange organization, and enterprise wide m igration. Developed project justification documentation along with highly detailed design and project plan to corporate investment team and sold the concept. In addition: Created standard baseline server configuration across enterprise. Designed a new

Symantec anti-virus hierarchy. Set-up Windows ISA proxy server, consolidated SQL servers, and implemented the first company intranet via Windows Share point services.

Network Engineer/Manager

Smartronix Inc.-Tampa, FL

January 2004 to December 2005

Contracted to support Lockheed Martin Corporation USCENTCOM Enterprise Network Contract. Promoted to Lead

Engineer/Manager within the first month of employment, a working manager position over 6 Sr. Level System

Engineers, my team was responsible for over 10 enterprise Global Area Coalition Networks of all classifications.

Migrated legacy WindowsNT/Exchange 5.5 domains to Windows 2003/Exchange 2003 enterprise. Responsible for the configuration and maintenance of root DNS and integrated Active Directory architecture. Configured and maintained secure Active Directory replication between sites and configured exchange routing architecture.

Established enterprise baseline performance metrics. Designed and maintained backup solution for all network area storage. Duty included full System Administration duties on each network.

Communications Computer Operator

US Air Force

January 1995 to December 2004

(More Info Available upon interview)

Sr Exchange Systems Engineer

TEKSYSTEMS Mar2010-Charleston, SC

Contracted to provide sustained support for the Navy Medicine Active Directory environment, consisting of

60,000+ users and electronic mailboxes. Primary responsibilities include the management of the Microsoft

Exchange environment, including, but not limited to, server maintenance (Windows and DoD required patching), information store maintenance, information security, general Exchange functionality. Additional technologies supported: Blackberry Enterprise Server Microsoft SMS, SharePoint, VMWare, Iron Mail, and Simple Sync in a

Military Enterprise environment. Designed migration strategy Active Directory 2010 and Exchange 2010 environment

Education

MS in Masters of Information Systems

American Sentinel University 2009

BS in Computer Information Systems

Columbia College of Missouri 2006

AS in Information Systems Technology

Community College Air Force 2001

Skills

- IT Management
- IT Strategy System Engineering and Architecture (Expert) Project/Program Management Cloud Computing (Azure, AWS, Google) Vendor

- Management Active Directory
- Azure -Office 365 Disaster Recovery
- Planning and Management Exchange
- SharePoint
- Teams Cyber Security
- Planning and Management Hardware
- Virtualization
- SQL

Certifications and Licenses

MCTS

MCITP

CompTIA Security+

CompTIA Network+

MCSE

CompTIA Project+